

avidleen16@gmail.com

0860611784

mww.linkedin.com/in/david-leen mww.davidleen.net

A highly motivated individual, with a first-class honours degree in Digital Media Design, from the University of Limerick. My studies have equipped me for a role in the design industry and areas such as UX/UI Design, Interaction Design and Graphic Design. Developed an excellent eye for detail due to the heavy demands of projects, research and deadlines, during my degree and in employment. Experience working in a multimedia/marketing company, as a digital designer and video editor. Gained many transferable skills, such as excellent team work, initiative, communication, time management and organisational skills. Possess a good working knowledge of many industry leading software applications, such as Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign and Premiere Pro. Keen to gain a role which allows me to further my knowledge and skills, along with an increased responsibility and the opportunity to utilise my design expertise at a leading and innovative company.



## Education

## 2017-Present Graphic Design & Illustration with Adobe Illustrator

ECollege Ireland.

### 2012-2016 Bachelor of Science in Digital Media Design **Graduated with First Class Honours**

University of Limerick, Limerick.

Key Course Content: Interaction Design, HCI, UX/UI, Interactive Multimedia, Sociology, Research Methods, Product Design, Web Design, Basic Programming, Audio/Video Production

### 2011–2012 QQI level 5 in Multimedia Production **Graduated with Distinction**

LCFE, Mulgrave Street Limerick.



## Experience

### VisitorFlix

Nexus Innovation Centre, Tierney Building, UL, Limerick.

Two periods of work at VisitorFlix, which is a digital media destination marketing company, with a comprehensive online tourist video library and guides of destinations, hotels, restaurants, activities and attractions. These videos are used for the client's own use and promotion and are also licenced to various partners such as Fáilte Ireland, car hire companies, airports, tour operators and accommodation providers as online video marketing content.

## 2016-Present Freelance Video Editor & Digital Media Designer

- · Video editing for a branch of the company called InFlightFlix, which focuses on video guides for the Wild Atlantic Way, featured onboard airlines. These videos are showcased on specific partner's transatlantic flights and websites.
- Created posters and images to accompany and highlight the airline's online inflight videos section.
- · Updated and uploaded individual client videos (that appear in the guides) to online platforms for distribution, client
- ·Video editing also focused on VisitorFlix's online tourist video library collection across the country.
- Digital content creation for potential new partners and existing clients, including mock-ups to showcase video guides and their features, libraries on various platforms, instructional and informative guides and display content for events.

### 2014–2015 Digital Media Designer

- Video editing for the company's online tourist video library and online platforms focused on Munster and Connacht.
- •Using in-house software to create individual client widgets (tailored video library), for use on their website and online.
- •Managing and updating content on the company website and hotel bedroom TV's service that displayed various client made videos and advertising.
- •Created graphics and posters for promotional use in videos, social media, online and for other marketing campaigns.

## 2006-2012 O'Grady's Centra/Gala **Shop Assistant**

The Courtyard, Fairhill, Killarney, Co.Kerry.



# Technical Skills & Knowledge

# **Software/Applications**

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- InDesign
- · Adobe XD
- Sketch & Invision
- Processing
- Premiere Pro, FCP 7 & X
- WordPress

### **Skills & Knowledge**

- Prototyping & Mock-ups
- Wireframing
- Basic HTML/CSS
- User Research
- Report Writing
- Persona Creation
- **Usability Testing**
- Storyboarding

# **Design Disciplines**

- · Interaction Design
- User Experience Design
- Product Design
- Graphic Design
- · Human Centred Design
- Human Computer Interaction



# Achievements & Interests

## **Achievements**

- UL Presidential Letter of Excellence Received five such letters, for achieving exceptional high grades during the completion of my degree
- Youth volunteer for Killarney Credit Union 2005 Certificate of merit awarded for work as a Youth Advisory Council Member at Killarney Credit Union

### References available on request.

### Interests

- · Sport Soccer, Golf, Basketball, Tennis, Snooker and Combat Sports
- Technology & Design, Video Games & Computers, TV & Film, Reading